Guide to the Carl Djerassi Papers SC0348
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- ORD book manuscript files and correspondence, Series 1
  - MSSSP CCIV: Spectra of Hydantoins II: Electron Impact Induced Fragmentation of Some Substituted Hydantoins by R.A. COrral, O.O. Orazi, A.M. Duffield and C. Djerassi (729), 1970-1971 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - MSSSP CCIV: Spectra of Hydantoins II: Electron Impact Induced Fragmentation of Some Substituted Hydantoins by R.A. COrral, O.O. Orazi, A.M. Duffield and C. Djerassi (729), 1970-1971 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Organic Chemical Applications of Magnetic Circular Dichroism by C. Djerassi. Bunnenberg and Elder (730), 1970-1971 (includes photos) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "Organic Chemical Applications…" (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - MSSSP CCII: Interaction of Remote Functional Groups in Acyclic Systems upon Electron Impact by M. Sheehand, R.J. Spangler, M. Ikeda, C. Djerassi (731), 1971 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Alkaloid Studies LXV: Confirmation of the Heptacyclic Structure of the Aspidosperma Obscurinervium Alkaloids through X-ray Analysis of Obscurinervine Hydrobromide by J. Kahrl, T. Gebroyesus, C. Djerassi (732), 1971 (includes photo and negative) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - MSSSP CCVI: Observation of the Fragmentation Olefinic Hydrocarbons by K.K. Mayer and C. Djerassi (733), 1971 (includes photos and negatives (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - MSSSP CCIII: The course of a Triple Hydrogen Migration in Esters of Trimellitic Anhydride by J. Cable and C. Djerassi (734), 1970-1971 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - MSSSP CCVII: Fragmentations des Ethers Insatures by J.P. Morizur, C. Djerassi (735), 1971 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - MSSSP CCI: The Fragmentation in Aliphatic Ketones in the Mass Spectrometer; A Detailed Study of Nonan-4-one Using Ion Kinetic Energy Spectroscopy by G. Faden, C. Djerassi, J .H. Beynon and R.M. Caprioli (736), 1970 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - MSSSP CCIX: Functional Group Interaction after Electron Impact; Anomalous Ether Cleavage in Bifunctional Benzyloxy Ethers by M. Sheehan, Spangler, and Djerassi (738), 1971 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - MCD Part XIII: A study on Purified Bovine Erythrocuprein by Weser, Bunnenberg, Cammack, Djerassi, Flohe, Thomas, Voelter (737), 1971 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - MCD Part XIV: Untersuchungen zur Struktur der Xanthinoxidase by Bayer, Voelter, Krauss (739), 1971 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Synthesis and Biological Activity of D-Bishomo Steroids by G. Eaden and C. Djerassi (743), 1971 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - MSSSP CCVIII: The Effect of Double Bonds Upon the Mclafferty Rearrangement of Carbonyl Compounds by J.R. Dias, Y.M. Sheikh and C. Djerassi (744), 1971 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - MSSSP CCK: Evidence for Transition States of Different Ring Sizes in the Loss of C4H8 from Phenyl n-butyl Ethers in the Mass Spectrometer by Yeo and Djerassi (745), 1971 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - MSSSP CCXIII: Effect of Ring Size Upon Electron Impact Induced Behavior of Steroidal Ketones by Popov, Eaden, and Djerassi (746), 1971 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "MSSSP CCXIII" (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - MSSSP CCXI: by Eaden, Popov, Djerassi (747), 1971-1972 (includes photos) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - MCD Studies XVII: MCD Spectra of Proteins; A New Method for the Quantitative Determination of Tryptophan by Barth, Records, Bunnenberg, Djerassi and Voelter (748), 1971-1972 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - MSSSP CCXV: Behavior of Phenyl-substituted α, β-unsaturated Ketones upon Electron Impact; Promotion of Hydrogen Rearrangement Processes by R.J. Liedtke, A.F. Gerrard, J. Diekman and C. Djerassi (749), 1971-1972 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - MCD studies XVI: Investigations of Same Conjugated Olefins by Dauben, Seeman, Wendschuh, Barth, Bunnenberg, Djerassi (751), 1971 (includes Negatives) (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - MSSSP CCXVI: Anomalous Cleavage Ions in Bifunctional Compounds Resulting from Participative Interaction by Dias and Djerassi (752), 1971 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - 5α-Pregn-9 (1l-ene-3β. 6α_diol-2f-one and 5α_cholesa-9(11), 20(22)-diene-3β, 6α_diol-23-one); Two Novel Steroids from the Starfish Acanthaster Planci by Y. Sheikh, B. Tursch, and C. Djerassi (753), 1972 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Alkaloid studies LXVI: Reactions of Some Aspidosperma Alkaloids with Metachloroperbenzoic Acid, Removal of the Angular Ethyl Group of Aspidospermine by T. Gebreyesus and C. Djerassi (754), 1971 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "Alkaloid studies LXVI" (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - MSSSP CCXII: Electron Impact Induced Triple Hydrogen Rearrangements and other Fragmentations of Alkyl Vinyl Ethers and Thioethers by M. Katon, D.A. Jaeger and C. Djerassi (755), 1971-1972 (includes Negatives) (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - MSSSP CCXIV: Electron Impact Induced Fragmentation of Simple Acetylenes by P.W. Woodgate, K. K. Mayer, and C. Djerassi (756), 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "MSSSP CCXIV" (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - MSSSP CCXVIII: The Electron Impact Induced Behavior of Terpenoid Esters of the Juvenile Hormone Class by R.J. Liedtke and C. Djerassi (757), 1971-1972 (includes negatives) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - A New Sterol from an Alcyonaria Species by J.P. Engelbrecht, B. Tursch and C. Djerassi (758), 1972 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Applications of Artificial Intelligence for Chemical Inference VIII: by Smith, Buchanan, Enqelmore, Duffield, Yeo, Feiqenbaum, Lederberg, Djerassi (760), 1972 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - MCD XVIII: Structure and the MCD of Saturated Ketones by L. Seamans, A. Moscowitz, G. Barth, E. Bunnenberg and C. Djerassi (761), 1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Photos and negatives from "MCD XVIII" (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - MCD studies XIX: '!he Determination of the Tyrosine:Tryptophan Ratio in Proteins (762), 1972 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - MCD XX: A Study on Purified Bovine APO-Erythrocuprein by Weser, Barth, Bunnenberg, Djerassi, Hartmann, Krauss, Voelcker, Voelter, and Voetsch (763), 1972 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 5α-cholesta-9(11), 17(20), 24-triene-3β, 6α-diol; A minor Genin from the starfish Acanthaster Planci by Y.M. Sheikh, B. Tursch and C. Djerassi (764), 1972 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - MCD studies XXIII: Indole Alkaloids (765), 1972 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - MSSSP CCXVII: Electron Impact Promoted Fragmentation of O-Methyl Oximes by Y.M. Sheikh, R.J. Liedtke, A.M. Duffield and C. Djerassi (766), 1972 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - MSSSP CCXIX: Identification of a Unidirectional Quadruple Hydrogen Transfer Process in 7-phenylhept-3-en-2-one-O-methyl Ether by R.J. Liedtke, Y.M. Sheikh, A.M. Duffield and C. Djerassi (769), 1972 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - MSSSP CCXX: Synthesis and Mass Spectra of 5α_cholest-8(9)- and 8(14)-en-7-ones by Ian Midgley and C. Djerassi (770), 1972 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - MSSSP CCXXXI: The Loss of Methyl from the (M-C2H4)± Ion of Butyrophenone by R. Torner and C. Djerassi (771), 1972 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Dog and Cat Population Explosion I, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Dog and Cat Population Explosion I, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Dog and Cat Population Explosion I, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Dog and Cat Population Explosion I, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Terpenoids LXVIII: 23_acetoxy-17-deoxy-7, 8-dihydroholothurinogenen; A New Triterpenoid Sapogenin from a Sea Cucumber by I. Rothbert, B. Tursch, C. Djerassi (773), 1972 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Synthesis of Corticosteroids from Marine Sources by J.E. Gurst, M.H. Sheikl and C. Djerassi (774), 1972 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Stereochemical Course of the Metal-Ammonia Reduction of 5g-cholest-8(14)-en-7-one; A Facile Synthesis of 14B-Steroids by I. Midgeley and C. Djerassi (775), 1972 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - MCD Studies XXII: Urinary Porphyr Determination; Lead Poisoning (776), 1972 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - MSSSP CCXXII: Delineation of Competing Fragmentation Pathways of Complex Molecules from a study of Metastable Ion Transitions of Deuterated Derivatives by D.H. Smith, A.M. Duffield and C. Djerassi (777), 1972 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - MSSSP CCXXIII: Ortho Interactions of Nitro Groups by K.B. Tomer, T. Gebreyesus and C. Djerassi (778), 1972 (includes photos) (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - The Structure of the High Energy (M-Ketone) + Ions from Acetanilide by R.B. Tamer, S. Hammerum and C. Djerassi (779), 1973 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - ORD Studies CXIX: The Effect of Ring Heroatoms on the Cotton Effect of Cyclohexanones by M. Cook and C. Djerassi (780), 1972-1973 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - MSSSP CCXXIV: Fragmentation of Cyclopropanes by J .R. Dias and C. Djerassi (782), 1972 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - MSSSP CCXXV: Sulfur Migration in the (M_C2H4) Ion of S-Ethyl Thiobenzoate by Tomer and Djerassi (783), 1972 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Science Editorial (785), 1973 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Massenspektometrie und ihre Anwendung auf strukturelle und stereochemische Probleme CCXXVI: Wasserabspaltung durch Elektronenstross von 3-hydroxy-5B-cholanen by H. Klein and C. Djerassi (786), 1972-1973 (includes photo and negative) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript: Birth Control Propects after 1984, 1971-1972 (includes photo) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Characterization of 3B-hydroxy-5_-choesta-9(1l), 20(22) dien-23-one-6_YL-B-D-6-deoxy Glucoside from the Starfish Acanthaster Planci by Y.H. Sheikh and C. Djerassi (788), 1973 (includes photo and Negatives) (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - MSSSP CCXXVIII: Application of ICR for Differentiation between Tautomers; Vinylthiol and Thioacetaldehyde by Tomer and Djerassi (789), 1973 (includes photos) (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - MSSSP CCXXXIII: On the Sterochemical Dependence of the Retro-Diels-Alder Reaction by S. Hammerum and C. Djerassi (790), 1973 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - New England Journal of Medicine, Editorial (791), 1973 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Application of Artificial Intelligence for Chemical Inference IX: Analysis of Mixtures without Prior Separation as Illustration for Estrogens by Smith, Buchanan, Engelmore, Adlercreutz and Djerassi (792), 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - MSSSP CCXXX: Perparation of 20-Iso and 17-Iso, 20-Iso-5α-cholestane-3β, 6α-diol Electron Impact Induced Fragmentation of steroidal Δ 17(20), Δ 20, (21) And Δ20(22) Olefins by Y.M. Sheikh and C. Djerassi (793) (includes photos and negatives) (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - The Carbon-13 Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Spectra of Keto Steroids by H. Eggert and C. Djerassi (794), 1973 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Application of Artificial Intelligence for Chemical Inference X: Intsum; A Data Interpretation and Summary Prognosis as Applied to the Collected Mass Spectra of Estrogenic steroids by Smith, Buchanan, White, Feigenbaum, Lederberg and Djerassi (795), 1973 (includes photos) (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - MCD studies XXI: The Magnetic Circular D Dichroism of Porphyrin Dications by G. Barth, R.E. Linder, E. Bunnenberg and C. Djerassi (797) (includes photos and negatives) (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - MSSSP CCXXIV: Alkyl Pyridyl Ketones by Tomer and Djerassi (799), 1973 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - MSSSP CCXXXI: Differentiation between Tautomeric Ion Structures (Phenol vs. Cyclohexadienone) by K. Tomer and C. Djerassi (800), 1973 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Steroids from Starfish by Y.M. Sheikh, M. Kaisin and C. Djerassi (801), 1973 (includes negatives) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - MSSSP CCXL: by R. Muccino and C. Djerassi (802), 1972 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "MSSSP CCXL" (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - MSSSP CCXXXIX: by R. Muccino and C. Djerassi (803), 1973 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The Population Council (804), 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Figures from "The Population Council" (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - MSSSP CCXXIX: Electron Impact Induced Fragmentation of Boric Acid Esters by S. Hammerum and C. Djerassi (806), 1973 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - MSSSP CCXXXVIII (807), 1973 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Fertility Control in the People's Republic of China; Present Situation and Future Prospects (808), 1973 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Fertility Control in the People's Republic of China; Present Situation and Future Prospects (808), 1973 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Medicine in China (Book Review) by C. Djerassi (809),1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - MCD studies XXIV: Application to Microsomal Cytochromes (812), 1973 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Photos, figures and negative from "MCD studies XXIV" (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - MSSSP CCXXXVII: Electron Impact Induced Hydrogen Losses and Migrations in Some Aromatic Amides by A.M. Duffield, G. Martino and C. Djerassi (814), 1973 (includes photos ani negatives) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Mechanism of Hydride Reduction of 1-Alkyn-3-ols by B. Grant and C. Djerassi (815), 1973 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - MCD studies XXVIII: Solvent Dependent Absorption and Magnetic Circular Dichroism Spectral studies of Triphenylcarbenium Ion by Mo et.al. (817), 1974 (includes photo and negative) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - MSSSP CCXLI: Investigation of the Electron Impact Induced Fragmentations of 1-hepten-3-OL by Ion Cyclotron Resonance by B. Grant and C. Djerassi (818), 1973-1974 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - MSSSP CCXLII: Applications of DADI; A Technique for Study of Metastable Ions to Mixture Analysis by D.H. Smith, C. Djerassi, X.H. Maurer and U. Rapp (819), 1974 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Addition of Dichlorocarbene to Steroidal Olefins; Preparation of a Steroisomer of Demethylgorqosterol-A cyclopropane Containing Marine Sterol by Y.M. Sheikh, J. LecLerque and C. Djerassi (820), 1973 (includes photo) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Capnellane: A New Tricyclic Sesquiterrene Skeleton from the Soft Coral Capnella Imbricata by B. Tursch, D. Daloze, J.C. Braekman, M. Kaisin, J.P. Engelbrecht, Y.M. Sheikh and C. Djerassi (822), 1974 (includes photo and negative) (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - MCD studies XXVI: Magnetic Circular Dichroism Spectra of Porphyrin Dianions by G. Barth, R.E. Linder, E. Bunnenberg and C. Djerassi (823), 1973-1974 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - MSSSP CCXLIII: Functional Group Interaction; Unusual Fragmentations of Amides as exemplified by Bipiperidyl Alkaloids by W. Fitch and C. Djerassi (824), 1974 (includes photos) (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - MCD studies XXVII: The Electronic Structure of Ring Halogenated Difluorophenylcarbenium Ions by Y.K. Mo, R.E. Linder, G. Barth, E. Bunnenberq and C. Djerassi (825), 1974 (includes photos am negatives) (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - MCD studies XXIV: Kinetische _ der Utersuchungen der Tryptophanoxidation in Proteinen by H. Eckstein, G. Barth, R.E. Linder, E. Bunnenberq and C. Djerassi (826), 1974 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - 25-Acetoxy-24-methyl-3β-5α, 6β-tri -hydroxycholestane: A Novel polyhydroxlated steroid from an Alcyonarian Moldowan, Tursch and C. Djerassi (827), 1974 (includes photo and negative) (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Operational Policy Aspects of Future Insect Control Methods (829), 1974-1975 (includes photo) (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Alkaloid Studies LXVII: Reinvestigation of the Proton Resonance Spectrum of Vindolinine at 300 MHz by L.J. Durhem, J.N. Schoolery, and C. Djerassi (830), 1974 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - MCD studies XXIII: The MCD Spectrum of Formaldehyde Vapor By R.E. Linder, G. Barth, E. Bunnenberq and C. Djerassi (831), 1974 (includes slides, photos and Negatives) (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - MCD Studies XXXV: A Comparison of Cytochrcmes P-450 am P-448 by J.H. Dawson, P.M. Dolinger, I.R. Trudell, G. Barth, R.E. Linder, E. Bunnenberq and C. Djerassi (832), 1974 (includes photo and negative) (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Steroids from Sponges (833), no date (includes photos and negatives) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - MCD studies XXIX: MCD Spectra of Magnesium and zinc Octaethylporphyrins and Their Five and Six Coordinated Complexes by G. Barth, R.E. Linder, E. Bunnenberq and C. Djerassi (834), 1974 (includes Negatives) (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - MCD studies XXX: Vibronic Intensity in Metalloporphyrins by R.E. Linder, G. Barth, E. Bunnenberq and C. Djerassi (835), 1974 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - MCD studies XXXII: CNDO Calculations of the Magnetic Circular Dichroism Spectra of 7-and 9-Met.hyladenine by R.E. Linder, H. Weiler Feilchenfeld, G. Barth, E. Bunnenberq and C. Djerassi (836), 1974 (includes slides, photos, and negatives) (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - A Stereoselective Synthesis of Two stereoisomers of Demethylgorqosterol by G.D. Anderson, T.J. PcMers, C. Djerassi, J. Fayos and J. Clardy (837), 1974 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Terpenoids LXX: The Structure of the Sea Cucumber Sapogenin Holotoxinagenin by W.L. Tan, C. Djerassi, J. Fayor and J. Clardy (838), 1974-1975 (includes Negative) (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - 2,6-Dibromophenol and 2,4,6, -Tribromophenols; Antiseptic Secondary Metabolites of Phoronopsis Viridis by Y. Sheikh and C. Djerassi (841), 1974 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - "Nuclear Power in the Middle East: Pawderkeg or Fire Extinguisher?," in Bulletin of the Atomic Scientist (842), 1975 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Men studies XXXI: Thioketones by Engelbrecht, Anderson, Linder, Barth, Bunnenberq, Djerassi, Seamans and Moscowitz (843), 1975 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - MCD studies XXXIV: Improved Instrumentation for MCD Measurements by G. Barth, J .H. Dawson, P.M. Dolinger, R.E. Linder, E. Bunnenberg and C. Djerassi (844), 1975 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Mao Tse-Tung says "Mankind ought to exercise self-control"; Freeman Dyson asks "What are the hidden costs of saying 'No'?": Perkin Medal Award Address, February 1975 (846) (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Synthesis of sterols with Modified Side Chains by Y.M. Sheikh and C. Djerassi (848), 1975 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - MSSSP CCXLV: [1] The Electron Impact Induced Fragmentation Reactions of 17-Oxygenated Progesterones by S. Hammerum and C. Djerassi (847), 1975 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - 24_-Methylcholestane-3β,5α,6β,l2β,25-Pentol 25 Monoacetate: A Novel Polyoxygenated Marine Sterol by J.M. Moldcwan, W.L. Tan and C. Djerassi (849), 1975 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Lab Notebooks, Series 2
  - Michael Bankiewicz, Ph.D., post-doc fellow, Aug. 1956- (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Alk Mali Kapoor (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - H. Bandas, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - James M. Bobbitt, Dept. of Chemistry, Wayne University, ca. 1955 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - A. Bowers, Organic Chem. Department, Wayne University, ca. 1954 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Jim Berdahl, 1958-59 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Burian-Eisenbraun, Dept. of Chemistry, June 1958-ca. Feb. 1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Sumner H. Burstein, Dept. of Chemistry, Wayne University,n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Robert Ehrlich, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - E. A. Wunderlich, Feb. 1952-Apr. 1952 (pp 1-10) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Robert Ehrlich #2 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - E. J. Eisinbaum, Dept. of Chemistry, Wayne University, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Eugene Farkas, research (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Sanford K. Figdor, “Investigations on the cactus alkaloid pilocereine obtained from Lophocereus Schottu” (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Jack Fishman, Dept. of Chemistry, Wayne University, 1952-54 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Eleanor J. Wilfred, Dept. of Chemistry, Wayne University, Sept. 1952- (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - J. J. Beereboom, Sept-Oct. 1955 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Lawrence Edwin Geller, June 1952-Jan. 1953 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Lawrence E. Geller, June 1956 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - B. Gilbert, Dept. of Chemistry (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - R. A. Finnegan (p. 155 on), Oct. 1958-July 1959 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Marvin Gorman, April 1952-Aug. 1954 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - James D. Gray, Dept. of Chemistry, Wayne University, Oct. 1956-June 1958 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - David Herbat, Org. Chem. Research Lab, Sept. 1957-May 1959 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - N. S. Grossley, Organic Chem. Lab, S.U., May 1959-Nov. 1961 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - N. S. Crossley (Box 6, Folder 21A)
  - M. A. Kielczewski (p. 30 on), Organic Chem. Dept., S. U., Oct. 1960- (Box 6, Folder 21A)
  - High No. 2 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - High No. 1 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Harinarayan Khastfir, Wayne University, May 1952-Nov. 1953 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Khastgir, Bk. IV, Jan. 1954- (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Gerald W. Krakower, Wayne University, May 1952-June 1958 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Peter R. Leeming, Dept. of Chemistry, Wayne University, Aug. 1956- (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Alfred Lippman, Aug. 1953- (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - L. H. Liu, April 53-Sept. 1954 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - R. McDonald, Sept. 1953-Dec. 1954 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Andrew John Manson, Wayne University, Sept. 1954-Aug. 1955 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - F. X. Markley, June 1955-Feb. 1957 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - P. Sengupta, Chem. Dept., Mar. 1953-Sept. 1953 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - R. Hodges (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Dr. Rafat Mirza, Dept. of Chemistry, Wayne University, Sep. 1954 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - “Investigations related to Pilocerine” Oct. 2, 1954-Nov. 11 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Peter S. Marfey, Wayne University, (“Organization of the Research Notebook”) Feb. 1952-June 1955 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Peter S. Marfey, Chem 384 (Organic Chem. Research), Wayne University (“Organization of the Research Notebook”), Feb. 27-1952- (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Lester A. Mitscher, Dept. of Organic Chem., Wayne University, Aug. 1955-July 1958 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Harold Monsimer, Wayne University, Apr. 1954-Nov. 1956 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - S. C. Pakrashi, Dept. of Chemistry, Wayne University, Mar. 1955-Jan. 1956 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Art Shu, May 1979-Aug. 1980 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - C. H. Robinson, July 1954-Oct. 1954 [2 packets of spectra included] (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Maurine Shamma, Sept. 1955-Aug. 1956 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - D. B. Thomas (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Dr. Riccardo Villotti, Dept. of Chemistry, Wayne University (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Chwang Siek Pak, Aug. 1955-June 1978 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Dr. Riccardo Villotti, Jan. 1959- [writing changes p. 85] (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Louis J. Visco, Wayne University, June 1952-June 1953 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Douglas P. White (p. 143 on), Chem. Dept., S. U., May 1960-Aug. 1960 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Michael H. Kohrman (p. 170 on), Chem. Dept., S.U., Oct. 1975-Mar. 1977 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - W. Brewer (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - M. W. Khalil (p. 184 on), June 1976-Sept. 1976 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Unidentified (p. 299 on), Sept. 1977 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Belig Berkoz (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Robert E. Wolff, Dec. 1957-Aug. 1958 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Warawa (?), Oct. 1958-June 1961 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Eric Lund (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Stauton (?) (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Wilkinson (?) (from p. 87 on) (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Edward Bunnenberg, Chem. Dept., Stanford, Oct. 1959-May 1960 (Box 8, Folder 52a)
  - Thomas George, Jan.1958-Feb. 1961 (Box 8, Folder 53A)
  - Thomas George, Sept. 1960- (Box 8, Folder 53B)
  - Philip A. Mayor, Dept. of Chemistry, Wayne University, Mar. 1957-Mar. 1960 (Box 8, Folder 54A)
  - Henry, Aug. 1954-Agu. 1955 (Box 8, Folder 54B)
  - Lee (?) (from p. 112 on), Apr. 1960-Aug. 1961 (Box 8, Folder 54B)